BENJAMIN PROTHE

Durham, NC | (724) 331-5297 | beprothe@gmail.com

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/benprothe/ | GitHub: github.com/xxblincolnxx

SUMMARY

I am a full-stack developer with 10 years of environmental consulting and lab experience. I pride myself on my reliability, consistency, patience, adaptability, honesty, integrity, and empathy. I believe that I have the organizational skills, persistence, creativity, and attention to detail to excel as a web developer.

DEVELOPER SKILLS

- JavaScript
- React.is
- Python
- HTML/CSS
- Django
- Git / GitHub/ Version Control Django Rest Framework
 - Dev Collaboration
 - CRUD Applications
 - Agile Development

Libraries and tools: React-Router, React-Context, Babel, Webpack, Sass, Axios, Charts.js, Moment.js, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Environs, Heroku, AWS, Django Registration Redux, Zoom, Bootstrap, Shoelace, Liveshare, Trello, Slack, beautifulsoup web scraping, Jupyter Notebooks

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE COURSE

2020 | Momentum Learning, Durham, NC

Vue.is

• AJAX

Modules:

- Front-end basics with HTML/CSS and vanilla JavaScript
- Back-end development with Django and Python

Collaboration / Industry Training:

- Version control with GitHub
- Remote collaboration
- Agile development methodology
- Terminal crash course

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, BIOLOGY

2008 | Geneva College, Beaver Falls, PA

WORK HISTORY

MONTROSE ENVIRONMENTAL | LABORATORY SERVICES | ENTHALPY ANALYTICAL, DURHAM, NC

2017-2020: EPA Method 325B | GCMS Analyst I 2017: GC & Field Services | GC/FTIR Analyst I

- Perform EPA Method analyses to determine pollutant sample concentrations
- Comply with Company Quality System to withstand agency and industry scrutiny
- Compile analytical reports for use in federal emissions reports
- Gas Chromatography (GC)
- Mass Spectrometry (MS)
- GCMS/ GC-FID /GC-TCD / FTIR (instrumentation)
- Wet Chemistry

GitHub: github.com/xxblincolnxx Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/benprothe/

WORK HISTORY (continued)

MONTROSE ENVIRONMENTAL | FIELD SERVICES | AIR, COMPLIANCE CONSULTANTS, INC. (ACQUISITION)

2016 - 2017: LDAR QA/QC Manager

2014 - 2015: Project Scientist II **2012 - 2013:** Project Scientist I

- Oversaw team during period of exponential revenue and project growth
- Achieved promotions at accelerated interval during entire duration of employment
- Managed projects, operations, and field teams to maintain accurate, auditable data output
- Built up training and standard procedures to accommodate increasingly larger clients with more demanding requirements
- Review regulations and permits to keep clients in compliance with changing regulations
- Conducted compliance, internal, and third party audits
- Wrote/managed project proposals

2010 - 2012: Scientist I and II

- Conducted Field Work for detecting fugitive emissions from hazardous piping
- Collected Samples for laboratory analysis
- Updated process flow diagrams for accurate emissions source inventory and eliminate ambiguity for field teammates
- Updated LDAR registries and manuals for compliance revisions and to apply field updates for accurate component inventories
- Attended compliance audits where field techniques, compliance records, and documentation were scrutinized by regulators

CHRISTIAN FELLOWSHIP ACADEMY

2009 - 2010: Science and Math Teacher

- Full time instructor; prepared lessons, tests, and lab activities for grades 6-10.
- Classes Taught: Biology, Physical Science, Earth Space Science, Life Science, and Algebra I.

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/benprothe/

GitHub: github.com/xxblincolnxx